{
	"riddles": [
		{
			"id": 0,
			"question": "The binary system uses powers of:",
			"answers": ["2", "10", "16"],
			"correct": "2"
		},
		{
			"id": 1,
			"question": "A computer program that converts assembly language to machine language is:",
			"answers": ["Compiler", "Interpreter", "Assembler"],
			"correct": "Assembler"
		},
		{
			"id": 2,
			"question": "ASCII stands for",
			"answers": ["American standard code for information interchange", "All purpose scientific code for information interchange", "American Scientific code for information interchange"],
			"correct": "American standard code for information interchange"
		},
		{
			"id": 3,
			"question": "The list of coded instructions is called",
			"answers": ["Computer program", "Algorithm", "Flowchart"],
			"correct": "Computer program"
		},
		{
			"id": 4,
			"question": "Which language was devised by Dr. Seymour Aubrey Papert?",
			"answers": ["COBOL", "LOGO", "FORTRAN"],
			"correct": "LOGO"
		},
		{
			"id": 5,
			"question": "The complete picture of data stored in database is known as",
			"answers": ["Record", "Schema", "DBMS"],
			"correct": "Schema"
		},
		{
			"id": 6,
			"question": "Compilers and interpreters are themselves",
			"answers": ["High-level language", "Codes", "Programs"],
			"correct": "Programs"
		},
		{
			"id": 7,
			"question": "A billionth of a second is defined as a",
			"answers": ["millisecond", "microsecond", "nanosecond"],
			"correct": "nanosecond"
		},
		{
			"id": 8,
			"question": "When was Apple Macintosh II microcomputer introduced in the market?",
			"answers": ["1964", "1983", "1970"],
			"correct": "1983"
		},
		{
			"id": 9,
			"question": "The arranging of data in a logical sequence is called:",
			"answers": ["sorting", "classifying", "summarizing"],
			"correct": "sorting"
		},
		{
			"id": 10,
			"question": "Who is the creator of the PASCAL language?",
			"answers": ["Niklaus Wirth", "Basic Pascal", "Donald Knuth"],
			"correct": "Niklaus Wirth"
		},
		{
			"id": 11,
			"question": "Which type device is a piece of equipment that receives information from a CPU?",
			"answers": ["Input", "Output", "CPU"],
			"correct": "Output"
		},
		{
			"id": 12,
			"question": "What is the language used by most of the DBMSs for helping their users to access data?",
			"answers": ["High level language", "Query language", "4GL"],
			"correct": "Query language"
		},
		{
			"id": 13,
			"question": "In SQL, which command is used to make permanent changes made by statements issue since the beginning of a transaction?",
			"answers": ["ZIP", "SAVE", "COMMIT"],
			"correct": "COMMIT"
		},
		{
			"id": 14,
			"question": "Periodically adding, changing and deleting file records is called file...",
			"answers": ["updating", "upgrading", "restructuring"],
			"correct": "updating"
		},
		{
			"id": 15,
			"question": "The relational model uses some unfamiliar terminology. A tuple is equivalent to a:",
			"answers": ["record", "field", "file"],
			"correct": "record"
		},
		{
			"id": 16,
			"question": "Which command is used to remove an index from the database in SQL?",
			"answers": ["DELETE INDEX", "DROP INDEX", "REMOVE INDEX"],
			"correct": "DROP INDEX"
		},
		{
			"id": 17,
			"question": "What name is given to the collection of facts, items of information or data which are related in some way?",
			"answers": ["Database", "Directory information", "Information tree"],
			"correct": "Database"
		},
		{
			"id": 18,
			"question": "In SQL, which of the following is not a Data Manipulation Language Commands?",
			"answers": ["DELETE", "UPDATE", "CREATE"],
			"correct": "CREATE"
		},
		{
			"id": 19,
			"question": "What is the abbreviation used for a software package that permits the users to create, retrieve and maintain records in a database?",
			"answers": ["DASD", "EMMS", "DBMS"],
			"correct": "DBMS"
		},
		{
			"id": 20,
			"question": "Which command is used to select distinct subject (SUB) from the table (BOOK)?",
			"answers": ["SELECT ALL FROM BOOK", "SELECT DISTINCT SUB FROM BOOK", "SELECT SUB FROM BOOK"],
			"correct": "SELECT DISTINCT SUB FROM BOOK"
		},
		{
			"id": 21,
			"question": "Which of the following TCP/IP protocol is used for transferring electronic mail messages from one machine to another?",
			"answers": ["FTP", "SNMP", "SMTP"],
			"correct": "SMTP"
		}
	]
}